(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T00:18:59.708147",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ホロレンジャー 生誕3Dヒーローショー
Holo Rangers Birth 3D Hero Show
迫るショッカー
Shocker approaches,
地獄の軍団
the army of hell.
我らをねらう 黒い影
A dark shadow targeting us,
世界の平和を 守るため
to protect the peace of the world.
ゴーゴーレッツゴー 輝くマシン
Go! Go! Let's go! The shining machine!
ライダー (ジャンプ！)
Rider (Jump!)
ライダー (キック！)
Rider (Kick!)
仮面ライダー 仮面ライダー
Kamen Rider, Kamen Rider!
ライダー ライダー
Rider, Rider!
ライダー (ジャンプ！)
Rider (Jump!)
ライダー (キック！)
Rider (Kick!)
仮面ライダー 仮面ライダー
Kamen Rider, Kamen Rider!
ライダー ライダー
Rider, Rider!
第1話 ヒーロー爆誕！？雪花ラミィの旅立ち！
[Episode 1: A Hero is Born?! Yukihana Lamy's Departure!]
あっちゅ！
Hot!
いや、火薬の量間違えて爆発させすぎちゃったよ。
No, they used the wrong amount of gunpowder and caused too big of an explosion!
もう、せっかくの眉毛が燃えちゃうよ。
Geez, my precious eyebrows are going to get singed!
あ！雪民さん、ありがとう！
Ah, Yukimi-san! Thank you!
お！みんな！今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Oh! Everyone! Thank you for coming today!
そうです！今日はラミィの誕生日です！
That's right! Today is Lamy's birthday!
そして、今年のラミィは一味違います！
And this year, Lamy is a little different!
今年も体力測定の力をつけてきたけど...
I've been working on my physical strength again this year...
みんな知ってる？何でラミィがあんなに頑張ってたか？
Do you know why Lamy was working so hard?
実はね...ヒーローになるためなんだ！
The truth is... it was to become a hero!
でも、ヒーローって言っても色んな形があるじゃん？
But heroes come in many different forms, right?
だから今日は、自分だけのヒーロー像を探す旅に出ようと思うの！
So today, I'm going to set off on a journey to find my own ideal hero!
な、なんだ！？
W-What is that?!
イーッ！
Yee!
いや、やめろ！
No, stop!
おりゃ！
Take this!
イーッ！
Yee!
キャー！
Kyaa!
イーッ！
Yee!
うわぁ！
Woah!
雪民さん！
Yukimi-san!
雪民さん！ラミィを守ってくれたの？
Yukimi-san! Did you protect me?
さっきもバイク片付けてくれたし！
You even cleaned up my motorcycle earlier!
雪民さんは本当に偉いなぁ！
You're really so wonderful, Yukimi-san!
よし、よし、よし、よし。
There, there, there, there.
あ！だいふくもいたの？
Ah, Daifuku, you were here too?
ちょっとまた敵が来ないか見はっといて。
Can you keep watch to make sure no more enemies show up?
今日はね、色んなゲストを呼んで、たくさんのヒーローを見ることができるから、楽しみだね！
Today, we've invited all kinds of guests, and we'll get to see lots of different heroes, so I'm really excited!
それじゃあ、雪花ラミィ、ヒーロー探しの旅に行ってきます！
Well then, Yukihana Lamy is setting off on her journey to find a hero!
なんで...なんでまた雪民ばっかり...
Why... Why is it always Yukimi...
僕だって...僕だって...
I can do it... I can do it too...
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ
Who's that? Who's that? Who's that?
空のかなたに踊る影
The shadow dancing high in the sky...
白い翼の
...with white wings...
ガッチャマン
...is Gatchaman!
命をかけて飛び出せば
When you risk your life and fly out,
科学忍法 火の鳥だ
that's the Science Ninja Art, Firebird!
飛べ 飛べ 飛べ ガッチャマン
Fly! Fly! Fly, Gatchaman!
行け 行け 行け ガッチャマン
Go! Go! Go, Gatchaman!
地球は一つ 地球は一つ
There is only one Earth, there is only one Earth!
おお ガッチャマン ガッチャマン
Oh, Gatchaman, Gatchaman!
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ
Who's that? Who's that? Who's that?
海の地獄に潜む影
The shadow lurking in the hell of the sea...
強い勇気の
...with powerful courage...
ガッチャマン
...is Gatchaman!
嵐をさいて雲きれば
When you rend the storm and tear through the clouds,
科学忍法 火の鳥だ
that's the Science Ninja Art, Firebird!
飛べ 飛べ 飛べ ガッチャマン
Fly! Fly! Fly, Gatchaman!
行け 行け 行け ガッチャマン
Go! Go! Go, Gatchaman!
地球は一つ 地球は一つ
There is only one Earth, there is only one Earth!
おお ガッチャマン ガッチャマン
Oh, Gatchaman, Gatchaman!
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ
Who's that? Who's that? Who's that?
ビルの谷間に忍ぶ影
The shadow hiding in a valley of buildings...
赤い血潮の
...with fiery red blood...
ガッチャマン
...is Gatchaman!
夕日を浴びて駆け出せば
When you bask in the sunset and run out,
科学忍法 火の鳥だ
that's the Science Ninja Art, Firebird!
飛べ 飛べ 飛べ ガッチャマン
Fly! Fly! Fly, Gatchaman!
行け 行け 行け ガッチャマン
Go! Go! Go, Gatchaman!
地球は一つ 地球は一つ
There is only one Earth, there is only one Earth!
おお ガッチャマン ガッチャマン
Oh, Gatchaman, Gatchaman!
キン肉マン Go Fight!
[Title: Kinnikuman Go Fight!]
ハッ ハッ
Ha! Ha!
Go! Go! Muscle!
リングに 稲妻走り
Lightning strikes the ring,
炎の 戦士をてらす
illuminating the fiery warriors.
飛び散れ キン肉ビーム
Jump in, Muscle Beam!
勝利に向かって
Heading towards victory...
私は（ドジで）強い（つもり）キン肉マン
...I am the (clumsily) strong (probably) Kinnikuman!
走る（すべる）見事に（ころぶ）
I run (and slip), brilliantly (and fall down)!
ああ 心に愛がなければ
Ah, if there is no love in your heart,
スーパーヒーローじゃないのさ
you are not a superhero!
キン肉マン Go Fight!
Kinnikuman, Go Fight!
ハッ ハッ
Ha! Ha!
Go! Go! Muscle!
嵐の 必殺技で
With a storm of finishing moves,
けちらす 超人レスラー
kicking around the superhuman wrestlers,
マットに 真っ赤な薔薇が
a bright red rose on the mat...
今夜も 咲くのさ
...will bloom once more tonight!
私は（ドジで）強い（つもり）キン肉マン
I am the (clumsily) strong (probably) Kinnikuman!
誰もが（誰も）待って（いない）
Is there anyone (no one) waiting for me (nobody)?
ああ 果てない夢を追いかけ
Ah, chasing the endless dream...
果てない夢を追いかけ (Uh~ Uh~ Uh~ Uh~)
I chase after the neverending dream (Uh~ Uh~ Uh~ Uh~)
スーパーヒーローになるのさ (Ha~)
of becoming a superhero (Ha~)
キン肉マン Go Fight!
Kinnikuman Go Fight!
私は (ドジで) 強い (つもり)
I am (clumsily) strong (probably)
キン肉マン
Kinnikuman!
走る (すべる) 見事に (ころぶ)
I run (slip), and gracefully (fall down).
ああ 心に愛がなければ
Ah, if there is no love in my heart,
スーパーヒーローじゃないのさ (Ha~)
then I'm not a superhero (Ha~)
キン肉マン Go Fight!
Kinnikuman Go Fight!
微か夕陽
[Song: Faint Sunset]
聞こえないように
As if not to hear,
俯く躯を
my cast-down body...
誰か包んで...
Someone please wrap it...
壊れる前に
before it breaks.
弾き出し嘲笑い
Spurning and laughing,
瞳を打つ
it strikes my eyes.
闇への 引き金
The trigger leading into the darkness.
踏み込む強さより
Rather than the strength to step forward,
抗う痛みなら
if it is the pain of resisting...
誰より撫でここで
soothing me here more than anyone,
食らう Conscience
devouring my conscience.
引き千切られたプライドが
My torn-apart pride
心に巻くブリザード
wraps a blizzard around my heart.
ねえ ここから出してよって
Hey, please let me out of here!
叫んでいいの？
Is it okay for me to scream?
埋もれた声は低い空が
The low sky always
いつも救ってくれたね
rescued my buried voice.
砕かれた幻想の果て
At the end of shattered illusions,
でも まだ終わらせない
but I still won't let it end!
My heart will doubt...?
悲しみ宿った
The sorrow that dwells
花びらに伝う
travels down the petals.
涙が堕ちた
My tears have fallen,
儚き結晶
a fleeting crystal.
未来さえ試されて
Even our future is tested
篩にかけて
and sifted through,
残った現実
leaving behind this reality.
寡黙に見つめ合う
Silently staring at each other,
夕陽はこの鼓動
the sunset will keep this heartbeat
生かしてくれるだろう
alive, won't it?
惑う With the truth
Straying with the truth.
転んだ今日がまとわりつく
Our fallen today clings to us,
萎れた感情伏せて
hiding our withered emotions.
ねえ 早く気付いてよって
Hey, please notice me quickly!
叫んでいいの？
Is it okay for me to scream?
傾いた世界に宿る
Dwelling in a tilted world,
道は見分けられるか
can you tell the paths apart?
ゲームは始まったばかり
The game has only just begun.
この世に潜む現在を
This present moment hidden in the world...
My heart will want...
いらない痛みなんてないんだと
Saying there is no such thing as useless pain,
素直な自分足して
I add to my honest self.
ねえ ここまで来たよって
Hey, I made it all the way here!
褒めてもいいの？
Is it okay to praise me?
埋もれた声は低い空が
The low sky always
いつも救ってくれたね
rescued my buried voice.
砕かれた幻想の果て
At the end of shattered illusions,
でも まだ終わらせない
but I still won't let it end!
My heart will believe
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
[Song: Mahou Sentai Magiranger]
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi, Magi, Magi Ranger
信じてフューチャー
Believe in the future
OK! オーライ! 勇気をこの手に
OK! All right! Courage is in your hands
旅立て!
Set off on a journey!
君が超えたいものは何?
What do you want to overcome?
大空 逆風 昨日の自分
The great sky, the headwind, your old self
立ち向かう時 揺れ動く
When you face them, you waver
その胸に湧き出すパワー
The power surging in your chest
グリーン グランド ピンク ストーム
Green Grand, Pink Storm
ブルー スプラッシュ イエロー サンダー
Blue Splash, Yellow Thunder
レッドファイヤー
Red Fire
冒険の始まりさ
This is the beginning of an adventure!
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi, Magi, Magi Ranger
限界チャレンジャー
Limit challenger
勇気という名の魔法を持ってる
We have the magic named courage
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi, Magi, Magi Ranger
夢見てフューチャー
Dream of the future
OK! オーライ! 明日をこの手に
OK! All right! Tomorrow is in our hands
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Magical Task Force Magiranger
旅立て!
Set off on a journey!
君が守りたいものは何?
What do you want to protect?
友情 プライド 見えない絆
Friendship, pride, invisible bonds
くじけそうな時 そばにいる
When you're about to fall, I'll be by your side
笑顔に初めて気がつく
Noticing your smile for the first time
タウロス フェアリー
Taurus, Fairy
マーメイド ガルーダ
Mermaid, Garuda
フェニックス
Phoenix
5つの手重ねたら
When our five hands are placed together
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi, Magi, Magi Ranger
限界チャレンジャー
Limit challenger
勇気が勝利の道を示すから
Because courage will show the path of victory
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi, Magi, Magi Ranger
信じてフューチャー
Believe in the future
OK! オーライ! この声よ届け
OK! All right! Send out your voice
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Magical Task Force Magiranger
旅立て!
Set off on a journey!
唸る大地 風は吹き抜け
The growling earth, the wind blows through
たゆたう水 走る雷 燃える炎
The swaying water, the racing lightning, the burning fire
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi, Magi, Magi Ranger
限界チャレンジャー
Limit challenger
勇気という名の魔法を持ってる
We have the magic named courage
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi, Magi, Magi Ranger
夢見てフューチャー
Dream of the future
OK! オーライ! 明日をこの手に
OK! All right! Tomorrow is in our hands
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Magical Task Force Magiranger
GO FIGHT! マジマジマジレンジャー
GO FIGHT! Magi, Magi, Magi Ranger
信じてフューチャー
Believe in the future
OK! オーライ! 勇気をこの手に
OK! All right! Courage is in our hands
魔法戦隊マジレンジャー
Magical Task Force Magiranger
旅立て!
Set off on a journey!
第２話 仲間の力！心が導くヒーローのカタチ！
[Episode 2: The Power of Friends! The Shape of a Hero Guided by the Heart!]
うーん、たくさんのヒーローと出会えて力はついたけど...
Hmm, I met a lot of heroes and gained power, but...
なんだか今一つピンと来ないんだよなぁ...
But somehow, it still hasn't quite clicked with me...
ラミィ、悩んでる顔してどうしたの？
Lamy, you look worried. What's wrong?
あ、かなた。そうなの。ヒーローってどうあるべきか分かんなくなっちゃって
Ah, Kanata. Yeah, I've become unsure of how a hero should be.
力があるだけじゃダメなんだ。大事なのは、その力をどう使うかだよ
Just having power isn't enough. What's important is how you use that power.
かなた…
Kanata...
握力だけじゃ、世界は変えられない
Grip strength alone can't change the world.
人々を、心を守るのも、ヒーローの大事な大事な仕事なんだから
Protecting people's hearts is also a very, very important job for a hero.
そっか。力で守れないものもあるよね
I see. There are things you can't protect with power alone, right?
そう！だからヒーローにも強い心が必要なんだ！
Exactly! That's why heroes need a strong heart, too!
どんなにピンチになっても、乗り越えるためにどんどん強くなる心が！
A heart that grows stronger and stronger to overcome any crisis!
さあ、僕と一緒に歌って、強い心を掴み取ろう！
Come on, sing with me and seize that strong heart!
うん！
Yeah!
プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリティでキュアキュア ふたりは
The pretty and curing two are
プリキュア！
Pretty Cure!
一難去ってまた一難 ぶっちゃけありえない！
One crisis after another, totally unbelievable!
制服着ててもふたりは むちゃくちゃタフだし
Even in school uniforms, the two of us are incredibly tough
お互いピンチを乗り越えるたび 強く近く（強く近く）なるね自閉症
Every time we overcome a crisis together, we become stronger and closer
Yeah!
your best! my best! 生きてるんだから 失敗なんてメじゃない！
Your best! My best! We're alive, so failure is nothing!
笑う門に福来るでしょ！ネガティブだってブッ飛ぶ〜！
Good fortune comes to those who laugh! Even negativity will fly away!
生命の花 咲かせて！思いっきり〜 もっとバリバリ！！
Let the flower of life bloom with all our might! Even more actively!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリティでキュアキュア ふたりは プリキュア！
The pretty and curing two are Pretty Cure!
たまには放課後のほほんと おしゃべり Very time!
Sometimes, having a carefree chat after school, very time!
ウワサは恋する乙女の ビタミン剤だもん
Rumors are vitamin supplements for a girl in love
闇夜に浮かんだ虹のかけ橋 ここに降りて（ここに降りて）奇跡☆
The rainbow bridge floating in the dark night, descending here is a miracle
Yeah!
your best! my best! 全力だから 友情、愛情、サイコー！
Your best! My best! Because we're going all out, friendship and love are the best!
論より証拠の輝くえくぼ 必殺技でハートキュン！
Dimples shining speak louder than words, a killer move to make hearts skip a beat!
瞳に、☆（ほし）映して！思いっきり〜 もっとキラキラ！！
Reflecting stars in our eyes with all our might! Even more sparkling!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリティでキュアキュア ふたりは プリキュア！
The pretty and curing two are Pretty Cure!
プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリキュア Chu Chu プリキュア Sha ba da ba da
Pretty Cure Chu Chu, Pretty Cure Sha ba da ba da
（プリキュア Chu Chu プリキュア Sha ba da ba da）
(Pretty Cure Chu Chu, Pretty Cure Sha ba da ba da)
Chu Chu Ah Chu Chu Ah
明日は明日の風吹く マジ意味わかんない
"Tomorrow's another day"; I seriously don't get what that means
今しか出来ない宿題 ガンバらなくっちゃ！
Homework that can only be done now, I've got to work hard!
真逆のキャラでもあい通じてる
Even with opposite personalities, we get through to each other
夢を生きる（夢を生きる）チカラ☆
The power to live our dreams
Yeah!
your best! my best! 生きてるんだから 失敗なんてメじゃない！
Your best! My best! We're alive, so failure is nothing!
笑う門に福来るでしょ！ネガティブだってブッ飛ぶ〜！
Good fortune comes to those who laugh! Even negativity will fly away!
生命の花 咲かせて！思いっきり〜 もっとバリバリ！！
Let the flower of life bloom with all our might! Even more actively!
プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア プリキュア
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure
プリティでキュアキュア ふたりは プリキュア！
The pretty and curing two are Pretty Cure!
プリキュア プリキュア (Chu wa)
Pretty Cure, Pretty Cure (Chu wa)
ありがとう、かなた！なんとなくヒーローって何かっていうのを掴めた気がするよ
Thank you, Kanata! I feel like I've gotten a grasp of what a hero is.
よかった！きっとラミィなら素敵なヒーローになれるよ
I'm glad! I'm sure you'll make a wonderful hero, Lamy.
その人を思いやる気持ちを忘れずにね
Don't forget that feeling of caring for others.
わかった！ラミィなりのヒーロー像、考えてみるよ！ありがとう！
Got it! I'll try thinking of my own vision of a hero! Thank you!
それじゃあ
Well then...
さらばー！
...farewell!
はあ、行っちゃった
Sigh, she's gone.
よし！この調子で次にいくぞ！
Alright! Let's keep this momentum and move to the next one!
あ！
Ah!
ごめんね、だいふく。
I'm sorry, Daifuku.
今忙しいの。後で構ってあげるから。
I'm busy right now. I'll play with you later.
なんで？なんで僕だけ見てくれないんだ？
Why? Why won't you look at only me?
うわあああん！
Waaah!
時に僕らは理想を語る非凡な才の歌人で
At times we are bards of uncommon talent recounting ideals,
またはキャピタリズムに屈する傀儡の卑しい子犬で
Or wretched puppies of puppets yielding to capitalism,
または虚構が書かれたボードを掲げるデモの一員で保存
Or members of a demonstration holding boards inscribed with fiction,
言わばあなたにとっての卑しい法螺吹き野郎の狼少年だ
So to speak, a wretched, bragging wolf boy to you.
名声を 体裁を 人生そのものを 潰しあおう
Let's crush fame, the establishment, and life itself,
怨んで 怨んで 怨んでもまた悔やんで
Resenting, resenting, resenting and regretting it once more,
描きたい存在に背中を刺される
Being stabbed in the back by the very existence I wanted to draw,
燃やして 燃やして 燃やしても手が震えて
Burning, burning, burning even as my hands tremble,
嘘を白昼堂々重ねて着込んだ
Stacking up lies in broad daylight,
分かって 分かって 分かって僕の正義を
Understand, understand, understand my justice,
無能な怪物を郷愁で焦がした
Scorched the incompetent monster with nostalgia,
妬んで 妬んで 妬んでいるまま選んだ
Jealous, jealous, choosing it while still being jealous,
その程度の茶茶な正解はいらない
I don't need a cheap correct answer of that degree.
時に僕らは希望を託す聖人じみた歌人で保存
At times we are saint-like bards entrusting hope,
またはマキャベリズムを隠した外見だけの置物で
Or mere ornaments hiding Machiavellism in appearance only,
または全てに噛みつく振りだけ得意なエキストラで
Or extras whose only skill is pretending to snap at everything,
やはりあなたにとっての卑しい法螺吹き野郎の狼少年だろう
Surely, you'd think of us as a wretched, bragging wolf boy.
現状の 展望も 変貌も 何もかもが 鬱陶しいんだ
The current prospects, transformations, everything is just annoying,
存在を 本望を 人生そのものを 潰しあおう
Let's crush our existence, true desires, and life itself,
怨んで 怨んで 怨んでもまた悔やんで
Resenting, resenting, resenting and regretting it once more,
描きたい存在に背中を刺される
Being stabbed in the back by the very existence I wanted to draw,
燃やして 燃やして 燃やしても手が震えて
Burning, burning, burning even as my hands tremble,
嘘を白昼堂々重ねて着込んだ
Stacking up lies in broad daylight,
分かって 分かって 分かって僕の正義を
Understand, understand, understand my justice,
無能な怪物を郷愁で焦がした
Scorched the incompetent monster with nostalgia,
妬んで 妬んで 妬んでいるまま選んだ
Jealous, jealous, choosing it while still being jealous,
その程度の茶茶な正解はいらない
I don't need a cheap correct answer of that degree.
時に僕らは思想を説く英雄的な歌人で
At times we are heroic bards admonishing ideology,
つまりあなたにとってのカリスマ気取った極悪非道なペテン師だ
In other words, to you, we are heinous, merciless swindlers putting on charismatic airs.
ねえ、生まれてから今日までの間 どれくらいのごはんで
Hey, from the time we were born until today, with how many meals
わたし達はできてるかな 毎日ありがとう
Have we been made? Thank you every day.
もし食卓から おいしいが消えてしまったら ああ、迷わずに
If delicious food were to disappear from the dining table, ah, without hesitation,
どこにいたって 何をしてたって 取り戻しにいこう
Wherever we are, whatever we are doing, let's go get it back.
あれは記念日の記憶
That is the memory of our anniversary,
何気ないあの味も
Even those casual flavors
忘れたりしない
We won't forget;
ずっと一緒だよって 伝えなくちゃ
We must convey that we are always together.
かならず！
Definitely!
守りたいこの味は キミと笑いあう毎日の
This flavor I want to protect is from laughing together every day,
いちばん傍で照らす あたたかい道しるべなんだ
Shining right by your side as a warm guide.
みんなと 今胸を熱くするオモイ 育んでこれからも
With everyone, our feelings warming our hearts right now, nurturing them into the future,
大切に刻もう キズナで結ぶスペシャリティ
Let's carve it preciously: a specialty bound by our bonds.
ホラ、キミに届く おいしいの中の たくさんのストーリー
Look, so many stories are packed inside the deliciousness reaching you!
めぐりめぐって ここにあるって 奇跡みたいだよ
After going around, it's like a miracle that we're right here.
やくそく！
I promise!
繋げたい今がある キミと分けあいたい未来へと
There's a present I want to connect, heading to a future I want to share with you.
くじけそうな時も 負けないココロで立ち向かう
Even when I feel like giving up, I'll face it with an unyielding heart.
みんなの しあわせなエナジーが作る この日々がうれしいよ
I'm so happy for these days created by everyone's happy energy.
デリシャスにあつまれ！パーティは続いていくね
Gather around deliciously! The party will keep on going.
世界中で今も
Even now, all across the world...
それぞれのストーリー
...there's a story for each and every one of us.
ひとりずつが できることを
Because each of us is doing...
がんばってるから
...the best we can!
かならず！
I swear!
守りたいこの味は キミと笑いあう毎日の
This flavor I want to protect is the warm guide...
いちばん傍で照らす あたたかい道しるべなんだ
...that shines closest to us in our everyday lives of laughing together.
みんなと 今胸を熱くするオモイ 育んでこれからも
From here on, let's keep nurturing these feelings that warm our hearts.
大切に刻もう キズナで結ぶスペシャリティ
Let's cherish and engrave this specialty bound by our bonds.
やくそく！
I promise!
繋げたい今がある キミと分けあいたい未来へと
There's a present I want to connect, heading to a future I want to share with you.
くじけそうな時も 負けないココロで立ち向かう
Even when I feel like giving up, I'll face it with an unyielding heart.
みんなの しあわせなエナジーが作る この日々がうれしいよ
I'm so happy for these days created by everyone's happy energy.
デリシャスにあつまれ！パーティは続いていくね
Gather around deliciously! The party will keep on going.
大好きなキズナで結ぶスペシャリティ
Let's cherish and engrave this specialty bound by our bonds.
第3話 間を超えて！ねぽらぼ絆ビームで奇跡を起こせ！
[Episode 3: Transcend the Rift! Create a Miracle with the Nepolabo Bond Beam!]
やっぱりねぽらぼだね！
Indeed, it's gotta be Nepolabo!
ねぽらぼー！
Nepolabo!
だいふく、やっと来てくれた！
Daifuku, you finally came!
許さない… 許さない…
I won't forgive you... I won't forgive you...
だ、だいふく？
D-Daifuku?
やみふく
[Yamifuku]
まさかあれは…
Don't tell me that's...
ラミィに構ってもらえず 負の感情が爆発して…
Since Lamy didn't pay attention to him, his negative emotions exploded...
闇落ちした、闇ふく…
...and he fell to the dark side. Yamifuku...
そんな！だいふく！元に戻って！
No way! Daifuku! Change back!
うるさい！
Shut up!
ラミィ！
Lamy!
こうなったら、力ずくでも元に戻してあげる！
In that case, I'll change you back even if I have to use force!
元に戻って！
Change back!
熱っ！
Hot!
強すぎじゃない、これ？
Isn't this way too strong?
強すぎる！
He's too strong!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
ど、どうだ？
H-How is it?
くそー！
Damn it!
だいふく！
Daifuku!
あ、ラミィ、待って！
Ah, Lamy, wait!
ちくしょうー！
Damn you!
ラミィ！
Lamy!
かまって…
Pay attention to me...
ヤミィ
[Yamii]
わー、ラミィちゃんが闇落ちさせられたー！
Oh no, Lamy-chan has been turned to the dark side!
これでラミィとずーっと一緒だ！
Now Lamy and I will be together forever!
ラミィが相手でも、止めるしかないよ！
Even if we're up against Lamy, we have to stop her!
確かに！ラミィはタフだしね！ちょっとくらい痛くても平気でしょ！
Exactly! Lamy is tough anyway! She'll be fine even if it hurts a little!
あ、ちょうどいいところに！いくよ、雪民！手ぇ貸して！
Oh, perfect timing! Go, Yukimin! Lend me a hand!
雪民さん、いけー！そりゃー！
Yukimi-san, go! Take that!
雪民、ごめーん！
Yukimin, I'm sorry!
いっけー！
Go!
かまって！
Pay attention to me!
強いー！
She's too strong!
うわあ！
Whoa!
ラミィ...
Lamy...
超ラミィ
Super Lamy!
えー！今度はラミィ、でっかくなっちゃったんだけどー！
Eh! Lamy got giant this time!
仕方ない、あれを使おう。
Can't be helped, let's use that.
あれ？
That?
そっか！
I see!
よし！
Alright!
みんな！力を貸して！ラミィのいいところをたくさん言って...
Everyone! Lend us your power! Tell us lots of Lamy's good qualities...
祝福の力（パワー）を貯めて、攻撃だ！
...and charge up the power of blessing, and attack!
ラミィ！ラミィ！
Lamy! Lamy!
よし、よし、よし。いい感じ、いい感じ。よし、このまま観客席のみんなも、
Good, good, good. Looking good, looking good. Alright, everyone in the audience,
ラミィのいいところ、めっちゃ言ってって！で、
keep calling out Lamy's good qualities! And...
うちらも言おう。
we should say them too.
え？うちらも言うの？
Eh? We're saying them too?
言うの？
We are?
ラミィのいいところ言っていこう。そうしたらラミィも元に戻るから。
Let's say Lamy's good qualities. If we do, Lamy will return to normal.
あ、確かに確かに。
Ah, indeed, indeed.
いつもの感じね。よし、ねねから！
Just like always. Alright, Nene first!
はい！
Yes!
まわしてって！よし、いけ！
Keep it going! Alright, go!
ラミィちゃんに言いたいことがある！
Lamy-chan, there is something I want to tell you!
なーにー？
What is it?
ねねのくだらないLINE、秒で返信してくれてありがとう！
Thank you for replying to my silly LINE messages in seconds!
え、優しい！優しい！
Eh, she's so nice! So nice!
あら、いいじゃない。これはちょっといいじゃない。
My, isn't that nice. That's actually pretty nice.
あ、パワー上がった！上がった、上がった！
Ah, the power went up! It went up, it went up!
よし、次、ポルカ、ポルカいく！
Alright, next, Polka, Polka's going!
ラミィに言いたいことがあります！
Lamy, there is something I want to tell you!
なーにー？
What is it?
いつもさ、こんな頼りないうちらのことまとめてくれたり、突っ込んでくれたりして、
You always keep us unreliable bunch together and commentate on our antics,
本当に感謝してるんだ。だからラミィ、お願い、元の姿に戻って！
I'm really grateful. So Lamy, please, return to your original self!
どうだ？いいんじゃない？
How is it? Isn't it good?
おお、上がった！上がった、上がった！
Oh, it went up! It went up, it went up!
いけ、いけ、いけ！次、ししろん！ししろんいけ！
Go, go, go! Next, Shishiron! Shishiron go!
よし。じゃあ、ラミィちゃんに言いたいことがある！
Alright, well then, Lamy-chan, there is something I want to tell you!
なーにー？
What is it?
いつも、ししろんが小ボケをいっぱいすると、全部に突っ込んでくれてありがとう！
Thank you for always reacting to my minor jokes whenever I make a bunch of them!
来い！めっちゃパワー上がるんじゃない？
Come on! Isn't the power going way up?
ありがとう。あ、もうちょっと、もうちょっと！
Thank you. Ah, just a little more, just a little more!
ねね、いけ！ねね、いけ、いけ！二個目？
Nene, go! Nene, go, go! A second one?
二個目、二個目！そう、二周、二周！
A second one, a second one! Yes, second round!
えー、ラミィちゃんに言いたいことがある！
Uh, Lamy-chan, there is something I want to tell you!
なーにー？
What is it?
秒で返信してくれるけど、スタンプで秒で終わらせようとするの、やめてー！
You reply in seconds, but stop trying to end the conversation with a stamp in seconds!
これ下がるんじゃない？大丈夫か？
Isn't this going to lower it? Is it okay?
あ、上がる、上がる、大丈夫。
Ah, it's going up, it's going up, it's okay.
これ上がる？あ、上がる、上がる。次、ポルカ、ポルカいく！
Is it going up? Ah, it is, it is. Next, Polka, Polka's going!
えー、ラミィに言いたいことがある！
Uh, Lamy, there is something I want to tell you!
なーにー？
What is it?
これをきっかけに、初期ラミィからやり直してみるのはどうでしょうかー！
Using this opportunity, how about starting over as "early-days Lamy"?!
バカ、お前！やめろ！やめろよ！
You dummy! Stop it! Stop that!
ほら、下がった！下がったって！バカたれ！
See, it went down! I told you it went down! You idiot!
ちょ、決める、決める、決める！決めるぞ！
Wait, finish it, finish it, finish it! Let's finish it!
ラミィちゃんに言いたいことがある！
Lamy-chan, there is something I want to tell you!
なーにー？
What is it?
いつも、ねぽらぼを大切にしてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for always treasuring Nepolabo!
おお、戻った！戻った、戻った！
Oh, it's back! It's back, it's back!
これは、どうなるんだ？え、どういうこと？やってくれるんじゃないの、これ？
What's going to happen to this? Eh, what do you mean? Isn't it going to do it?
あ、撃った！撃った、撃った！
Ah, it shot! It shot, it shot!
え、これは？あ、でも、これはパワーが貯まったんじゃないか？
Eh, what is this? Ah, but didn't the power charge up?
よし、よし、よし、ラミィ、元に戻ってくれ！
Alright, alright, alright, Lamy, please go back to normal!
いけ！ねぽらぼ絆ビーム！
Go! Nepolabo Bonds Beam!
戻って！ラミィー！
Return to normal! Lamy!
ラミィー！
Lamy!
あ、ラミィ！ラミィ！
Ah, Lamy! Lamy!
う、うう...ラミィは一体...
Ugh, ooh... What in the world did I...
あ、元に戻った！よかった！大福の力で闇落ちしてたんだよ。
Ah, she returned to normal! Thank goodness! You were corrupted by Daifuku's power.
いや、でも正直普段のラミィと全然変わんなかったから、うん。元に戻ってよかった。
Well, honestly, you were no different from the usual Lamy, so yeah. Glad you're back.
あ！え？お、あれ？大福！
Ah! Eh? Oh, look! Daifuku!
大福...ごめんなさい、ちゃんと見てあげられなくて...
Daifuku... I'm sorry, I couldn't look after you properly...
あ、ラミィ...
Ah, Lamy...
他人を思いやる気持ちが大事って教わったばかりなのに、うまくできなくて、ごめんね。
Even though I was just taught that having consideration for others is important, I couldn't do it right, I'm sorry.
やっぱりラミィには、大福や雪民さんがいないと駄目なの。
After all, Lamy cannot do without Daifuku and Yukimin.
ラミィ...
Lamy...
大福...ずっとずっと一緒だよ！
Daifuku... We'll be together forever and ever!
[完]
[Fin]
イェーイ！
Yeah!
はい、ということで、みんなラミィの生誕祭どうだったでしょうか？
So, everyone, how did you like Lamy's Birthday Festival?
面白かった！ 最高だった！
It was so fun! It was awesome!
ラミィ、誕生日おめでとう！ ありがとう！
Happy birthday, Lamy! Thank you!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ということでね、まだ終わりませんよ！
With that being said, we are not done yet!
重大告知が、２つあります！
I have two major announcements!
まずは、こちら！
First, here is this!
雪花ラミィ 誕生日記念2025グッズ！
Yukihana Lamy Birthday Celebration 2025 Goods!
ということで、詳しく紹介していきたいと思います。まずは、こちら！
So, I'd like to introduce them in detail. First up is this!
ドン！ アクリル…アクリル…
Boom! Acrylic... Acrylic...
アクリルスタンド！
Acrylic Stand!
テーマはですね、この後紹介いたしますフード付きタオルを身に付けたラミィの元気な姿となっております！
The theme is an energetic Lamy wearing the hooded towel we'll introduce next!
みんな飾ってね！ 飾るね！ 可愛い！
Everyone, please display it! We will! So cute!
続いては、こちら！ ドン！ おそろいトレーナー！
Next up is this! Boom! Matching Sweatshirt!
うわ、これ欲しかったやつ！ 可愛い！ これ欲しかった！
Wow, I really wanted this! So cute! I wanted this!
これはですね、サイバー衣装のトレーナーとおそろいのデザインとなっております。
This design matches the sweatshirt of my cyber outfit.
みんなラミィとおそろいにして着てね！ イェーイ！
Everyone, please wear it to match Lamy! Yeah!
続いては、こちら！
Next up is this!
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー ファンタジー私服衣装バージョンということで、
Plushie Keyring: Fantasy Casual Outfit Version!
ユニーリアのね、あの夏衣装を身にまとったラミィのぬいぐるみキーホルダーとなっております。
It's a Lamy plushie keyring dressed in her Yukilator summer outfit.
これをね、身に付けて色んなところ、ラミィと一緒にお出かけしてください！
Please put it on and go on outings to various places with Lamy!
そして、続いては、こちら！
And next up is this!
雪民フード付きタオルとなっております！ 可愛い！
It's a Yukimin Hooded Towel! So cute!
これね、あの雪民さんの顔がフードになっているタオルね。
For this one, a Yukimin's face forms the hood of the towel.
雪民さんがそこに居るけど、会話してるわ。
A Yukimin is right there, and they are talking.
今後ね、イベントとかあった時に、こういうのを身に付けてアピールしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you wear this to show your support at future events!
そして！ フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And! The Full Set Purchase Bonus is this!
雪花ラミィ 箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入り描き下ろしポストカードとなっております！
It's a newly drawn postcard with my foil-stamped signature and message!
みんなこれやって、イェーイ！
Everyone do this, yeah!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ということで、以上、雪花ラミィ誕生日記念2025グッズでした！
So, that was all for the Yukihana Lamy Birthday Celebration 2025 Goods!
おめでとう！ ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
そして、告知２つ目！ 何じゃ？
And the second announcement! What is it?
こちらは、新曲となっております！
It's a new original song!
この配信の後、21時から、フルアニメーションMVが公開されます！
After this stream, starting at 21:00, a full animation MV will be released!
そうなんです。初めてのフルアニメーションMVとなっております。
Yes. It's my first ever full animation MV.
みんな見てね！ 楽しみ！
Everyone, please watch it! We can't wait!
各種音楽サイトのリリースはこの後０時から配信されますので、よろしくお願いします！
It'll be released on various music streaming sites at midnight tonight, so please check it out!
はい、ということで、みんな今日はたくさんたくさんありがとう！
Alright, thank you so much, everyone, for today!
おめでとう！ ありがとうね！
Congratulations! Thank you!
バイバイ！ バイバイ！ ありがとう！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye! Thank you!
こっち、こっち、バイバイ！ ありがとうね！
This way, this way, bye-bye! Thank you!
ということで、最後に新曲、聴いていってください。
So, lastly, please listen to my new song.
それでは聴いてください。無敵☆本気だサバイバー！
Please listen to: Muteki Honki da Survivor!
ギリギリの綱渡り
Walking a tightrope on the edge
弱音はポケットの奥
Hiding my weaknesses deep inside my pocket
しまい込んだら ただ進むだけ
Once tucked away, all that's left is to move forward
こけたって 即リスタート
Even if I stumble, I'll restart instantly
そこからがスタートライン
Because that's where the starting line begins
もう止まらないよ
I'm not stopping anymore!
迷いなんて もう No No
No more hesitations, No No!
不器用でも 前へ
Even if I'm clumsy, I'll move forward
しょげてるヒマはなし
There's no time to feel down,
ハイテンションでいこうじゃん
so let's go with high tension!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー！
Invincible and dead-serious, a survivor!
ゼロからでも何度だって
No matter how many times, even from zero,
メンタル最強モードです 見ててね★
I'm in my strongest mental mode, so watch me!
限界☆歓迎チャレンジャー！
Limits are welcome, challenger!
そう不安なんてさ 笑い飛ばそう
Yeah, let's just laugh away any anxiety.
最前線 君次第
At the absolute front line, it's up to you!
さぁいくよ ready go ついてきてよね★
Now here we go, ready go! Make sure to keep up!
トラブルさえ追い風
Even trouble is a tailwind!
ピンチもドキドキのスパイス
Even a pinch is just thrilling spice!
Bring it on! 胸を張れ
Bring it on! Stand tall and proud!
遠回りも Go Go
Taking the long way around too, Go Go!
転んでも Try だ！
Even if I fall, I'll keep trying!
自分史上 一番へ
Heading to the best version of myself in history!
アクセル全開 ノンストップ！
Accelerator fully open, non-stop!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー！
Invincible and dead-serious, a survivor!
ブレーキなんてお飾りでしょ？
Brakes are just for decoration, right?
ハート高鳴りモードです 感じて★
My heart is in throbbing mode, feel it!
完全☆燃焼フィニッシャー！
A complete, high-combustion finisher!
そう誰より強く 夢を叫ぼう
Yeah, let's shout our dreams louder than anyone!
最終章 君次第
The final chapter is up to you!
さぁ行こう Ready Go 置いてかないから★
Now let's go, Ready Go! I won't leave you behind!
最強☆最愛チームメイツ！
The strongest, most beloved teammates!
君の声が パワーソース
Your voice is my power source!
輝いて 駆け抜けてこう
Let's shine and run right through!
未来へ Fly high...
Fly high into the future...
超ハイテンションでいこうじゃん！！
Let's go with ultra-high tension!!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー！
Invincible and dead-serious, a survivor!
ゼロからでも何度だって
No matter how many times, even from zero,
メンタル最強モードです 見ててね★
I'm in my strongest mental mode, so watch me!
限界☆歓迎チャレンジャー！
Limits are welcome, challenger!
そう不安なんてさ 笑い飛ばそう
Yeah, let's just laugh away any anxiety.
最前線 君次第
At the absolute front line, it's up to you!
さぁいくよ ready go もっともっと！ ついてきてよね★
Now here we go, ready go! More and more! Keep up!
みんな、今日のライブ、どうだった？
Everyone, how was today's live show?
ラミィ、ヒーローになれたかな？
Do you think Lamy was able to become a hero?
新曲も、今までのラミィにはない、かっこいい曲だったでしょ？
The new song featured a side of Lamy you haven't seen, right?
みんなの感想、今日のハッシュタグをつけていっぱい聞かせてね！
Let me hear lots of your thoughts using today's hashtag!
そして、この配信のあと、21時から...
And after this stream, starting at 21:00...
新曲「無敵☆本気だサバイバー！」の...
the new song "Invincible, Dead-Serious Survivor!"...
フルアニメーションMVが公開されます！
...full animation MV will be released!
ついにやってきました、フルアニメーション！
It's finally here, a full animation!
今回のMVには、ラミィの大好きなものがたくさん詰まっています！
This MV is packed full of things Lamy absolutely loves!
このライブのあと、直接MVに飛ぶようになっているので...
After this live show, you'll be redirected straight to the MV...
みんなこのまま待っててね！
...so everyone, please wait right here!
さて、まだもう少し時間があるから...
Well, since we still have a little more time...
MVをチラ見せしちゃいます！
I'm going to give you a sneak peek of the MV!
どうぞ！
Here you go!
無敵☆本気だサバイバー！
Invincible and dead-serious, a survivor!
ゼロからでも何度だって
No matter how many times, even from zero,
メンタル最強モードです 見ててね★
I'm in my strongest mental mode, so watch me!
限界☆歓迎チャレンジャー！
Limits are welcome, challenger!
そう不安なんてさ 笑い飛ばそう
Yeah, let's just laugh away any anxiety.
最前線 君次第
At the absolute front line, it's up to you!
さぁいくよ ready go ついてきてよね★
Now here we go, ready go! Make sure to keep up!
Woah-oh-oh-oh yeah
このあと ミュージックビデオ公開！
[The Music Video will be released after this!]
ヤゴウ
YAGOO
ヤミィ
Yamy
雪花ラミィ
Yukihana Lamy
ホロレンジ演 生配信3Dヒーローショー
HoloRanger: Live Stream 3D Hero Show